<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Felix T Platten</title>
    <link href="f618.info/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="f618.info"/>
    <updated>2020-09-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>f618.info</id>
    
      <author>
        <name>Felix T Platten</name>
        <email>felixtplatten@gmail.com</email>
      </author>
    
    
    <entry>
      <title>ECsemblage Magazine</title>
      <link href="/writing/ecsemblage-magazine/"/>
      <updated>2020-09-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/writing/ecsemblage-magazine/</id>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first post on my shiny new website. In the midst of the first London quarantine (prefacing with first is a safe bet) Evening-Class began work on a mail art inspired magazine. The skinny rag in question attempts to collage the collective’s disparate interests and positions with each member producing four pages which are pulled apart and scattered throughout the issue. My entry amounts to a semi-sensical materialist nonsense picture essay (ugh) which patchworks recent ideas on craft, death n’ ceremony. I cannot emphasise enough the effect that Phippe Nitchse’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.exitinternational.net/sarco/&quot;&gt;euphaniaisa machine&lt;/a&gt; has had on my thinking, so maybe this output can be viewed as another way of my subconscious stressing its importance. Reluctant to finish, or rather to submit my work Michael Wallace (online anon) collected my documents and put together the layout. Thank you, Herr Wallace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2w9rnfcy7mm78.cloudfront.net/9122362/large_32f868af1668a9e308b97466aab52aba.png?1602772399?bc=0&quot; alt=&quot;ECsemblage Singles&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ECsemblage can be purchased here on &lt;a href=&quot;https://eveningclass.bigcartel.com/product/ecsembling-1&quot;&gt;Bigcartel&lt;/a&gt; . All proceeds will be donated to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/artistsfundartists&quot;&gt;Artists Fund Artists&lt;/a&gt; campaign, which at the time of publication was directing all profit towards Black artists in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d2w9rnfcy7mm78.cloudfront.net/9122361/large_2452b0ff9fa252895d3c1e59e917fdde.png?1602772398?bc=0&quot; alt=&quot;ECsemblage Doubles&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
  </feed>
